<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>QSECO.FR</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on QSECO.FR</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>QSECO.FR Consulting</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Porting GnuCOBOL to IBM i</title><link>/research/porting-gnucobol-ibmi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/porting-gnucobol-ibmi/</guid><description>I’ve successfully ported GnuCOBOL to IBM i, and it is now available in the repo.qseco.fr IBM i yum repository. It can now be installed using yum install gnucobol and a specfile is available in our specfiles repository.
The following terminal log demonstrates its use:
bash-4.4$ uname -a OS400 FLINT 2 7 00XX000XXXXX Os bash-4.4$ cat hello.cob IDENTIFICATION DIVISION. PROGRAM-ID. Hello-world. PROCEDURE DIVISION. DISPLAY &amp;quot;Hello, world!&amp;quot;. STOP RUN. bash-4.4$ cobc -x hello.</description></item><item><title>IBM i 'hello world' in ILE C</title><link>/tutorials/hello-world-ile-c/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/tutorials/hello-world-ile-c/</guid><description>This tutorial will guide you through writing a simple Hello World application in ILE C and running it.
Requirements:
Basic C knowledge TN5250 Client IBM i V5R4 or Higher Compilers and dev tools installed on the i box. Create Source Physical Files Source code files on IBM i are stored in special kinds of Physical Files. These files have source members, which would effectively be your individual source files.</description></item><item><title>Starting Domino 10 Community Edition using systemd on Ubuntu 18.04</title><link>/plumbing/domino-systemd/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/plumbing/domino-systemd/</guid><description>The included startup scripts with the installer do not work on Ubuntu 18.04, and some of the examples available are more complex than necessary. The following simple systemd stanza will do the job just fine:
[Unit] Description=IBM Domino Server After=syslog.target network.target [Service] User=notes LimitNOFILE=60000 ExecStart=/bin/bash /opt/ibm/domino/bin/server WorkingDirectory=/local/notesdata [Install] WantedBy=multi-user.target Copy this file to /etc/systemd/system, and issue a systemctl daemon-reload command. Then enable the service using systemctl enable domino and start Domino 10 with systemctl start domino.</description></item><item><title>Fixing ‘JRE libraries are missing or not compatible….’ on Traveler installation</title><link>/plumbing/fixing-jre-missing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/plumbing/fixing-jre-missing/</guid><description>On modern Ubuntu Linux (18.04 LTS in my case), the InstallAnywhere installer fails with the following error:
JRE libraries are missing or not compatible.... IBM provides the following article to troubleshoot this issue:
https://www-01.ibm.com/support/docview.wss?uid=ibm10737993
Sadly enough, the information and work around in this article is not entirely accurate. The reason why the installer fails is because it relies on an included JRE, which is 32-bit only (even though the applications are 64-bit).</description></item><item><title>Demystifying AS/400 DASD</title><link>/research/demystifying-as400-dasd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/demystifying-as400-dasd/</guid><description>There seem to be quite a few misconceptions about AS/400 hard drives, commonly referred to as DASD (directly attached storage device). It is commonly known that only IBM-supplied DASD work, and typically only the FRUs listed. The big question though is “why is this the case?&amp;quot;.
Spinning disks die eventually. At the moment, generic SCSI disks are fairly commonly available, however, the FRUs to keep old AS/400 alive for hobbyist and archival purposes are becoming more and more scarce, with the supply eventually drying up.</description></item><item><title/><link>/services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/services/</guid><description>I am a senior penetration tester with extensive hands-on experience with both blue and red team environments. My expertise goes beyond delivery of just findings and I am well-versed in both implementing short-term fixes as well as rolling out a long term end-to-end security programme.
Experience I have a significant level of hands-on experience with legacy and fringe systems - unlike most application and system security consultants, I have real world experience with often inacessible technologies such as RPG, COBOL, IBM i, AIX and z/Arch.</description></item><item><title>Blog</title><link>/blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/</guid><description>Research Demystifying AS/400 DASD Porting GnuCOBOL to IBM i Tutorials IBM i ‘Hello World’ in ILE C Digital plumbing Starting Domino 10 Community Edition using systemd on Ubuntu 18.04 Fixing “JRE libraries are missing or not compatible….” on Traveler installation</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/contact/</guid><description> Email: friedkiwi@qseco.fr Telephone: +32 9 298 14 89</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/</guid><description>Mono on IBM i A successful community-supported port of Mono to IBM i, supporting DB2 and ASP.net
Link: mono.qseco.fr
repo.qseco.fr The largest repository of third party open source libraries and applications for IBM i
Link: repo.qseco.fr</description></item></channel></rss>