<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Researches on QSECO.FR</title><link>/research/</link><description>Recent content in Researches on QSECO.FR</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>QSECO.FR Consulting</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PCT-15 Audio decoding</title><link>/research/pct-15/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/pct-15/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just watched the recently released Techmoan video titled &amp;ldquo;Sony&amp;rsquo;s forgotten ‘80s Picture Phone&amp;rdquo;. As with all of his videos, I found it quite interesting and he has uploaded the audio files so I could do an attempt at trying to decode it.</description></item><item><title>Porting GnuCOBOL to IBM i</title><link>/research/porting-gnucobol-ibmi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/porting-gnucobol-ibmi/</guid><description>I’ve successfully ported GnuCOBOL to IBM i, and it is now available in the repo.qseco.fr IBM i yum repository. It can now be installed using yum install gnucobol and a specfile is available in our specfiles repository.
The following terminal log demonstrates its use:
bash-4.4$ uname -a OS400 FLINT 2 7 00XX000XXXXX Os bash-4.4$ cat hello.cob IDENTIFICATION DIVISION. PROGRAM-ID. Hello-world. PROCEDURE DIVISION. DISPLAY &amp;quot;Hello, world!&amp;quot;. STOP RUN. bash-4.4$ cobc -x hello.</description></item><item><title>Demystifying AS/400 DASD</title><link>/research/demystifying-as400-dasd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/research/demystifying-as400-dasd/</guid><description>There seem to be quite a few misconceptions about AS/400 hard drives, commonly referred to as DASD (directly attached storage device). It is commonly known that only IBM-supplied DASD work, and typically only the FRUs listed. The big question though is “why is this the case?&amp;quot;.
Spinning disks die eventually. At the moment, generic SCSI disks are fairly commonly available, however, the FRUs to keep old AS/400 alive for hobbyist and archival purposes are becoming more and more scarce, with the supply eventually drying up.</description></item></channel></rss>